Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/joanneburke-0690906 (LinkedIn) github.com/JoanneBurke (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Customer Insight Analytics Segmentation

Certifications

Data Science with Python -- 22 course boot camp

Data Science and Machine Learning with Python - Hands On!

TensorFlow in Practice Specialization

Honors-Awards

Photography Awards
Deans List

Joanne Burke

Data Scientist at MUFG

Irvine, California

Summary

Joanne possesses a keen and precise ability to translate data into profitable business initiatives, marketing insights, and C-level reporting.

Data Scientist, Actuary (ASA), and Cornell University graduate, Joanne is a valuable addition to any team.

She has project management and junior staff management experience. Joanne has built Machine Learning models to predict wi-fi costs and prescriptions per day within a 1% accuracy. Also, Joanne completed Data Camp's Data Scientist with Python boot camp and is knowledgeable in SciKit Learn, h2o.ai, TensorFlow, and Natural Language Processing (NLP).

Connection invitations are very welcome!

Experience

MUFG
Data Scientist
February 2020 - Present (2 months)
Irvine, CA

Including Kaiser Permanente, Panasonic, and Omdena (#AIForGood)
Data Scientist Short-Term Contractor
March 2017 - Present (3 years 1 month)
Irvine, CA

- * Implemented an NLP LDA/CoRex topic model and designed a TensorFlow BiLSTM classification neural network to identify important newspaper articles for a Washington DC think-tank.
- * Created an Auto Machine Learning model in python and h2o.ai to predict daily prescriptions for mission-critical planned pharmacy expansions within 1% accuracy.

- * Designed a Python prototype for the company's first ever machine learning process to estimate in-flight Wi-Fi prices. Because of a successful prototype, the project was green-lighted and now enables sales to estimate revenue for incoming airlines.
- * Cleaned input data using Elastisearch and story-boarded rich visuals in Power BI to demonstrate in-flight movie selection behavior for movie rental pricing decisions.
- * Wrote SAS, SQL, and Perl algorithms to create macroeconomic research reports for

C-level management.

- * Programmed complex ETL mission-critical data pipelines for 300 daily processes.
- * Oversaw pricing models that fed KBB website negotiated new car values.
- * Created Tableau dashboard with drill-down heat map visualizations for C-level partners.
- * Mined unstructured and non-standardized data for modeling factors by programming fuzzy logic algorithms with syntactic parsing and natural language processing techniques.

Omdena

Machine Learning (ML) Engineer, Community Builder and Mentor September 2019 - Present (7 months)

Palo Alto, CA - remote worker

- · Al for Good project to connect land conflicts in India with policies for restoration utilizing NLP, semi-supervised topic models, NLTK & spaCy, NER, TensorFlow RNNs and Machine Learning concepts.
- · Because of exemplary performance in the challenge, I was offered to join Omdena's Community Building initiatives and Mentor on new challenges.

Catalina Marketing Marketing Analytics Manager July 2003 - October 2016 (13 years 4 months) Irvine, California

- · Evaluated test versus control incremental brand volume and Return on Investment (ROI) measures for Nestle, Del Monte, and other Consumer Packaged Goods (CPG) companies that printed Catalina coupons utilizing the world's largest shopper history database.
- · Developed and validated insights from program measurement leading to new and continued multi-million dollar coupon contracts with leading CPG clients.

- · Designed a Point of Entry analysis illustrating trips progression through a category over time that was integrated department-wide in key client work.
- · Utilized high-level SAS programming concepts to analyze and garner omnichannel consumer insights from shopping survey data for analytics leadership.
- · Collaborated with sales from concept to presentation to quantify the value of next shopping order coupon response to the retailer based on a CPG coupon promotion leading to new Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) and actionable insights.
- · Constructed a million-shopper Millennial segment using SAS data techniques leading to a new, company-wide personalized shopper group for coupon programming.
- · Presented complex technical content in plain language to Sales Directors and VPs.
- · Created reporting standards for test versus control program KPIs measurement.
- · Programmed precise test versus control brand volume measurement methods for advertising prints with razor-thin margins for error.
- · Generated and consulted on in-depth consumer life-cycle behavioral data modeling for Gerber leading to path-to-purchase knowledge and better coupon program development.
- · Maintained fast-paced project management with many leading CPG clients.

Anthem

Actuarial Senior Associate 1998 - 2003 (5 years)

Thousand Oaks, CA

- · Managed annual Medicare Risk ACR annual reporting.
- · Calculated and reported quarterly profitability measures and forecast projections.
- · Applied SAS and SQL to produce analytical studies on Medicare Supplement benefits utilization, pricing, and trends for reporting and product design purposes.
- · Designed premium schedule for SmartChoice Medicare Supplement plans that performed 25% better than target.
- · Coordinated data criteria from finance, claims, and actuarial departments to design corporate medical benefits claims data warehouse for financial reporting.
- · Led intradepartmental project to test claims data warehouse for data quality.
- · Worked daily with Vice President and Chief Actuary.

Education

Cornell University
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Mathematics

Society of Actuaries
Associate Society of Actuaries, Actuarial Science